Bhanupal Singh Rathore

software developer



Personal Info

Phone 7406452928

E-mail

bhanupalsingh15@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhanusingh-b3070b9b/



Skills

JavaScript	
React.js + Redux	••••
Java	••••
Pyhton	••••
Hadoop	••••
Android	
scala	
Node.js	
shell script	



Certificates

Big Data Foundations - Level 1 By IBM

Hadoop Programming - Level 1 By IBM

Java Training By IIT Bombay

BRIEF SNAPSHOT

Research & Development Engineer with around 1 year experience in startup environment.

Good knowledge on application development using Java , JavaScript , React , Node.js and python.

Deep knowledge on REST APIs design.

Very good understanding of MVC framework and trained to follow the MVC for application development.

Knowledge of Play, Spring Boot, Redux, Hibernate frameworks.

Worked on database optimization as well as code optimization.

Knowledge on writing SQL queries and analyzing the SQL queries.

Knowledge of HTML, Bootstrap and JavaScript for client side application development.



present

Experience

2017-05 - Software developer

FullStack Developer at BlueTalon (Contract Basis).

Responsibility

vital labs

- Responsibility of stability of Bluetalon product.
- Writing new REST APIs, Migrating existing servlet calls to REST APIs.
- · Resolving the bugs in existing code and optimizing the code.

Worked on Android Project for a startup company.

2017-01 - Trainee 2017-05 Infosys

Trained on Java, Python, Hibernet, Restful Api, Enterprise Appliation. project undertaken – Question bank Archival System for Infosys end to end implementation.



Education

2013-07 - Institute Of Technology, Nirma University

2017-05 B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering

GPA - 8.01



Academic projects

Sentiment Analysis using spark

Dataset used - twitter, Amazon review, Imdb. At real Time it fetches tweet from twitter and predict particular tweet is positive, negative or neutral. same for amazon dataset and give rating to particular product based on reviews of that product.

Youtube Data Analysis using Hadoop

Basic Analysis based on offline available youtube data. Like – most watched video , Top 5 categories with maximum no of video uploaded , top rated video

Online Voting System Android App with Facial Recognition

Voting Android App by that user can able to do voting from anywhere without waiting in long queue.we use Backendless service for verification purpose and snapdragon sdk for facial recognition purpose.

Smart attendance Management System Android App

Faculty just need to click a picture of class and attendance are automatically granted to all present student. For that we use facial recognition. It save lot of time in taking attendance and store attendance directly in database.